# Johnnie Gonzalez

Elizabeth, New Jersey 07208 | 862-220-1841 | johnnie.agonz71@gmail.com | Github | Blog | LinkedIn

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React.js and Redux.js based programming and a background in architectural design. Strong skills in team work, time management, problem solving, and self learning. Striving to help lead in innovative design and green technology with a passion for all that is sustainable.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby | Rails | Active Record | JavaScript | React | Redux | CSS | HTML | Photoshop | PostgreSQL | SQL | SQLite | Version control | Auth

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Eco Share - Frontend | Backend | Video Demo

A fun interactive social media application where creatives can come together and share their eco-friendly designs.

- Utilized Ruby on Rails, Active Record in backend; JavaScript, React.js, Redux.js in frontend
- Implemented Ruby's Serializer gem to present certain data such as user data
- Follower Feed algorithm to filter out the designs of the current users follows Home page displays the designs of the users the user follows

## Ez Task - Frontend | Backend | Video Demo

A clean and simple single-page application where users can view/create tasks and delete accordingly.

- Utilized Ruby on Rails, Active Record in backend. Vanilla JavaScript in frontend
- Create, Edit. Delete tasks render to DOM without refresh
- Task visibility for walk by security enabling user to hide tasks at the click of a button

## Avatar - Github | Video Demo

Fun Interactive Ruby CLI game that a user can explore the world of Pandora

- Utilized Ruby on Rails, and Active Record to access a Sglite3 Database
- Implemented TTY Prompt and prompt.select so user can explore different walkthroughs
- User stats affected Set up incrementing and decrementing stats to database Depending on the route stats can be affected (health, food...etc..)
- Implemented a song from Avatar Soundtrack At start of game music turns on plays throughout and at end of game music turns off

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Solutions Architecture** Verona, New Jersey Architectural Intern 09/2019 - 03/2020

- Created blueprints and 3D floor plans based on client specifications, suggested changes as needed
- Performed detailed measurements at client site and applied to the schematics
- Worked with vendors to ensure timely delivery of orders to meet project deadlines and win bids

OTG Newark, New Jersey Bartender/Server 02/2016 - 03/2020

- Ensured customer satisfaction at high volume airport bar, working with a variety of clientele
- Performed a myriad of tasks as needed to keep multiple restaurants efficiently running
- Stocked inventory, estimated needs, replenished orders; opened and closed restaurant

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School New York, NY 09/2020 - 12/2020 Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Cranford, NJ

01/2016- 12/2018

**Union County College** Associate of Science - AS, Architecture/Engineering Societies - Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society